☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING] Shit! Shit!
该死
We're going down! We're going down!
我们在下行
Yeah, no shit, Harrington!
可不是呢  哈灵顿
- Why don't these buttons work?! - [STEVE SCREAMS]
这按钮怎么不好用
[ERICA] Press the button!
按按钮
What do you think I'm doing?!
你以为我在干什么
Come on, press something! Just press the button!
快按点什么  按按钮
- [SCREAMS] - [ERICA] Push it!
按啊
- [CRASHING] - [ALL GRUNTING]
- [STEVE] Oh! - [ROBIN WINCES]
[STEVE] My groin.
我的腹股沟
It fell on my groin.
掉在我的腹股沟上了
Dustin! [STRAINS]
达斯汀
- [ROBIN SIGHS] - Get this off of me!
把这个搬开
[STEVE] I can't move.
我动不了
[GRUNTS]
Is everyone okay?
大家都还好吗
Yeah, I'm great, now that I know that
是啊  我好极了
Russians can't design elevators!
我现在知道苏联人不会设计电梯了
I think we've clearly established that those buttons don't work.
我想我们已确定了那些按钮不好使
They're buttons. They have to do something.
那是按钮  肯定有功能的
Yeah, if we had a keycard.
是啊  如果我们有钥匙卡的话
- A what? - It's an electronic lock.
-什么  -电子锁
Same as the loading dock door. If we don't have a keycard,
跟装卸区门一样  如果我们没有钥匙卡
- it won't operate, meaning... - We're stuck in here.
-就打不开  所以  -我们困在这里了
Yeah.
是啊
Just so you nerds are aware,
你们这些呆子要知道
I'm supposed to be spending the night at Tina's,
我今晚本该去蒂娜家过夜的
and Tina always covers for me.
蒂娜总替我掩护
But if I'm not home for Uncle Jack's party tomorrow
但如果我明天不回家参加杰克叔叔的派对
and my mom finds out you three are responsible,
我妈妈发现是你们害的
she's gonna hunt you down, one by one, and slit your throat.
她会一个个地找到你们  割了你们的喉
I don't care about Tina!
我才不在乎蒂娜
Or Uncle Jack's party!
或杰克叔叔的派对
Your mom's not gonna be able to find us
你妈妈是找不到我们的
if we're dead in a Russian elevator!
因为我们要死在苏联电梯里了
[DUSTIN] Hey.
What if we climbed out?
要不我们爬出去
[DUSTIN'S GRUNTS ECHO]
[STEVE EXHALES SHARPLY]
What were you saying about climbing?
你刚刚说要爬吗
[STEVE'S VOICE ECHOES]
Looks like somebody's home.
看来有人在家
[DOOR HINGE CREAKING]
[LOW FREQUENCY PULSING]
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗
[PULSING CONTINUES]
[HOPPER PANTING]
[FLOORBOARDS CREAKING]
[PULSING CONTINUES]
[HOPPER GASPS]
[HOPPER EXHALES SHARPLY]
Where's that coming from?
哪传来的
[PULSING INTENSIFIES]
[WHISPERS] It's below us.
在我们下面
[HOPPER GRUNTS]
[PULSING CONTINUES LOUDLY]
[BOTH BREATHING RAPIDLY]
[SUSPENSEFUL SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
海斯
[DISTANT CLANKING]
[FAINT MALE VOICE]
[DISTANT RATCHETING NOISE]
[MEN SPEAKING IN RUSSIAN]
Hey, dipshits!
混蛋
[METALLIC TOOL CLATTERS]
Hawkins PD. Hands in the air.
霍金斯警局  手举起来
Don't make me say it again!
别逼我再说一次
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
English.
英语
[HOPPER] You speak English?
你们说英语吗
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
I can't understand you!
我听不懂
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
I can't understand you.
我听不懂
- [SPEAKING RUSSIAN] - No understand!
听不懂
- [THUDDING FOOTSTEPS] - Hopper!
霍普
[THUDDING CONTINUES]
[MUFFLED GROANING]
[MUFFLED YELLING]
[HOPPER] Don't move!
别动
Drop the gun.
放下枪
Drop it!
放下
You understand what I'm saying, big guy?
你听得懂吗  大块头
Drop the weapon.
放下武器
[IN RUSSIAN ACCENT] Or what?
否则呢
You going to shoot?
你要开枪吗
Good.
很好
[HOPPER] So you do understand what I'm saying, huh?
看来你听得懂
And, yeah,
是的
you don't put that thing away, I'm gonna blow some daylight
你不放下枪  我就给你的蠢脑袋
into that thick skull of yours.
开开光
No.
不
You won't do that.
你不会的
Why's that?
为什么
Because you are policeman.
因为你是警察
Policemen have rules.
警察有底线
Oh, yeah?
是吗
[GUN CLICKS]
Wanna test that theory?
想试试看吗
I'm gonna count to three.
我数到三
One,
一
two,
二
three!
三
[HOPPER GRUNTS]
[YELLING]
[FIGHTING GRUNTS]
[BULLETS RICOCHETING]
[JOYCE SCREAMS, GRUNTS]
[HOPPER YELLS]
[FIGHTING GRUNTS]
[GROANS, COUGHS]
[GRIGORI WAILS IN PAIN]
[BOTH PANTING]
[JOYCE] Hopper!
霍普
- Oh, shit. - [GRIGORI GRUNTS]
该死
[HOPPER] Go!
跑
[GUNFIRE]
[GRUNTS]
[HOPPER] Move, Joyce!
快跑  乔伊
- [JOYCE] Oh, God. - [HOPPER] Come on, Smirnoff.
-天呐  -走  司木露[伏特加品牌]
You're coming with us!
你跟我们来
- [HOPPER] Go, go, go! - [COCKS ASSAULT RIFLE]
快走
[JOYCE SCREAMS]
[YELLS]
[HOPPER] Let's go! Let's go!
快走
Move it, Smirnoff! Move it!
快走  司木露  走
Run!
跑
[GRUNTING]
Joyce! Drive!
乔伊  开车
[KEYS CLATTER]
- Come on, Joyce! Quit screwin' around! - Are you kidding me?
-快  乔伊  别瞎闹了  -你开玩笑吗
[STRAINING]
- Shit! - [HOPPER] Go!
-该死  -快走
Joyce, drive.
乔伊  开车
- I'm trying! - Joyce, please, drive!
-我尽力了  -乔伊  快开车
Drive!
开车
[YELLING]
[HOPPER] Get us outta here!
快带我们离开
[ENGINE ROARS]
[JOYCE SCREAMS]
[SCREAMS]
[BOTH SCREAM]
[HOPPER] Oh, God!
天呐
[JOYCE] Hang on!
坐稳
[GRUNTING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
[PANTING]
Still think it was our government?
还觉得是我们政府搞鬼吗
[PANTING]
[DRAMATIC SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
怪奇物语  第三季 第五集
第五章 失灵者
[PHONE RINGING]
[RINGING CONTINUES]
God, shut up!
天呐  闭嘴
[RINGING CONTINUES]
[GROANS]
- Hello? - Jonathan.
-喂  -乔纳森
Do you realize what time it is?
你知道现在几点吗
Listen to me, okay?
听我说
It's 6:00 a.m. and, uh,
才早上6点
I had a late night with Fagin and the gang, so...
我昨晚跟费根他们玩到很晚
- I'm at the hospital with Driscoll. - What?
-我在德里斯科尔住的医院  -什么
急诊
She's been sedated for a few hours
她已被药物昏迷几小时了
and the doctors are still running tests.
医生们还在做测试
Nancy, please tell me you're joking.
南茜  拜托告诉我你在开玩笑
It's not a joke. And, yes, I know I'm insane
不是开玩笑  是  我知道我疯了
and irrational and out of touch, but can you save your lecture,
不理智  不现实  但别训我了
because I really don't give a shit right now. I just...
因为我现在真的不在乎
I need you to put me on the phone
我需要你找你弟弟
with your brother.
来听电话
- What? - Jonathan...
-什么  -乔纳森
Please.
求你
Uh...
He's not even here.
他都不在家
Where is he?
他人呢
Is he safe?
他安全吗
Why wouldn't he be safe?
他为什么会不安全
Nancy?
南茜
Why wouldn't he be safe?
他为什么会不安全
[STEAM HISSING]
[HOPPER] Son of a bitch.
该死
Son of a bitch!
[HOPPER COUGHS]
Okay, a magnet? Magnets?
好  磁铁
- Do you know "magnet"? Magnet? - [SPEAKING RUSSIAN] Magnit.
-你知道磁铁吗  -磁铁
Yes, magnit.
对  磁铁
Okay, so, uh, magnit...
好的  磁铁
on my... my fridge,
我冰箱上的
my icebox, and then they...
我的冰盒子上的  它们
they fell.
掉下来了
They demagnetized, stopped working. Uh, do you understand?
消磁了  不能用了  你懂吗
Da.
嗯
Okay, so is that because of the machines that you're working on?
那是因为你们在弄的机器吗
- Machina. - Machina, machina, yes.
-机器  -对  机器
[IMITATES REVVING ENGINE]
Da, da, machina.
嗯嗯  机器
- Machina, machina! - Yes, machina...
-机器  -对  机器
Vroom, vroom.
嗡嗡
Oh, not... not the car.
不  不是车
The machines at Hess Farm where...
海斯农场的机器
- where we kidnapped you... - Joyce, please!
-我们绑架你的地方  -乔伊  拜托
You're givin' me a headache, both of you!
你俩要让我头疼死了
Hold on, please. One minute.
等一下  稍等
[JOYCE] Hey.
I am making progress.
我可有进展呢
- Progress. - Yeah.
-进展  -是啊
What have you learned, huh?
你都知道了什么
You learned that Smirnoff over there...
你知道司木露
- [JOYCE] Alexei. - Smirnoff is Russian
-阿列克西  -司木露是苏联人
and works for Starcourt,
为星庭工作
two things we already knew.
这我们都知道了
Thought we knew.
以为我们知道
But now we know-know, because I've confirmed them.
但现在我们能确定了  因为我证实了
You're welcome.
不客气哦
Yeah? Why don't you confirm whether this baby'll start, huh?
是吗  你证实一下这玩意能不能启动吧
- [HOPPER] Keep it in park, please. - Yeah, duh!
-拉着手刹  -当然了
You do... do something useful.
你做点有用的事啊
- You do something useful. - [SIGHS]
你去做啊
- [JOYCE SCOFFS] - [GROANS]
[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
[ELECTRIC CRACKLING]
[SIGHS]
It's not working.
启动不了
Try it again.
再试试
[ENGINE TURNS OVER]
Shit.
该死
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
- [ELECTRIC CRACKLING] - Hey. Hey. [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Stop, stop!
停下
Shut up, Smirnoff!
闭嘴  司木露
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN RAPIDLY]
Aw, come on! D'you hear me?
拜托  你听到了吗
I said shut your damn...
我说你闭...
[HIGH-PITCHED SQUEALING]
Shit!
该死
Oh, Jesus.
天呐
[JOYCE GASPS]
[HOPPER] Whoa!
[GASPS]
Stop.
停下
[JOYCE] I thought this friend of yours lived in Illinois.
我以为你的朋友住在伊利诺伊州呢
He's not really a friend. He's more like an acquaintance.
他算不上是朋友  就是个熟人
Oh? Okay, well...
好吧
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. Keep up, keep up, keep up.
跟上
- Easy. - [INSECTS BUZZING]
轻点
Okay, so this acquaintance...
好  这位熟人
- lives in Illinois? Correct? - [HOPPER] Yeah, yeah.
-住在伊利诺伊州吧  -对
[JOYCE] So we're walking to Illinois?
我们要走去伊利诺伊州吗
Yeah, yeah, we're gonna walk to Illinois.
是的  我们要走去伊利诺伊州
You know, I figure we'll get there by, like, Friday evening.
我觉得我们星期五晚上就能到
I hope that works for your schedule. Jesus Christ, Joyce.
希望合你的日程  天呐  乔伊
- We're not walking to Illinois, okay? - Well, then what are we doing?
我们不会走去伊利诺伊州的  好吗 - 那我们在干什么
I don't know, okay?
我不知道
I will... I will figure something out.
我会想出办法的
Isn't there someone in Indiana who speaks Russian that...
难道印第安纳州就没有会俄语的吗
You know what? I'm all ears, Joyce.
洗耳恭听  乔伊
I'm all ears.
你有办法吗
I'm all ears!
你说啊
[JOYCE] I mean, fine.
好吧
Just saying.
就说说
Gah!
Ugh!
[SIGHS]
[HOPPER] Damn it.
该死
I found him.
我找到他了
[MAX] Where is he?
他在哪
Woods.
林子里
- [TV STATIC HISSING] - Woods?
He's with... Will's mom.
他跟威尔的妈妈在一起
My... My mom?
我妈妈
What are they doing?
他们在干什么
Ill... annoy.
伊...诺伊
They're going to Ill-annoy.
他们要去伊拉诺伊
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR] - [KAREN] Mike! Breakfast!
迈克  吃早餐
Not now, Mom!
现在没空  妈妈
Illinois? Illinois, like the state?
伊利诺伊州吗
The state of Illinois?
[STAMMERS] Ill-annoy.
伊拉诺伊
[TAP STOPS]
[MAX] Does it still hurt?
还痛吗
Only when I talk.
只有说话的时候
Well, it's a good thing you're not Mike, then.
那幸好你不是迈克
"Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah." And you'd be in constant pain.
你会一直疼的
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
[MIKE] Something's not right.
这不对劲  霍普一整个夏天都死盯着我
I can't get Hopper off my back all summer,
now all of a sudden, he's hiking with Will's mom to Illinois?
现在他突然要跟威尔的妈妈徒步去伊利诺伊州了
And Dustin's MIA, too?
达斯汀也不见踪影
I mean, this can't be a coincidence.
这不可能是巧合
What does it matter?
那又怎样
The bottom line is, they're not here.
重点是  他们不在
- It's up to us. - Up to us to do what exactly?
-得靠我们了  -靠我们做什么
Find Billy and stop him.
找到比利  阻止他
Okay, yeah, that's a really nice sentiment,
好吧  这是好
but even if El could find him again,
但就算一一还能找到他
and that's a pretty big if, then what?
那还不一定呢  然后呢
We burn the shit out of him
我们烤焦他
and make sure he doesn't escape this time.
确保他这次不逃跑
- Okay, then what? - Then we win.
-好  然后呢  -然后我们就赢了
No, see, that's the problem.
不  瞧  这就是问题所在
We don't. We don't win.
我们赢不了
We got the Mind Flayer out of Will before
我们之前把吸灵魔从威尔身体里驱逐了
and he just came right back.
可他又卷土重来
We don't just have to stop Billy,
我们不光要阻止比利
we have to stop the Mind Flayer.
我们得阻止吸灵魔
- How in the hell do we do that? - I don't know.
-那要怎么做到  -我不知道
Maybe El does.
或许一一知道
What are they still doing in there?
她们怎么还在里面
I don't know.
我不知道
Girls just like hanging out in bathrooms.
女孩就喜欢一起待在厕所里
Why?
为什么
- I mean, I don't know. - They're conspiring against me.
-我不知道  -她们在密谋搞我
That's what you're concerned about now?
你现在还担心这个
It's not my main concern.
不是我最担心的事
- It's just a sub-concern. - I thought it was already over.
-是次要担心  -我以为你们都结束了
It's not over, okay? We're just taking a break.
没结束  我们只是暂时分手
She said she dumped your ass.
她说她甩掉你了
- That doesn't sound like a break. - [MAX] It wasn't!
-那不像是暂时分手  -的确不是
You guys do realize
你们知道我们还能
we can still hear everything you're saying, right?
听见你们说的一切吧
[LAUGHS]
[WHISPERS] Conspiring.
说对了吧
- I told you, they're conspiring. - [KNOCK AT DOOR]
她们就是在密谋搞我
Not now, Mom!
现在没空  妈妈
[NANCY] Mike, open the door.
迈克  开门
[DUSTIN] Code red, I repeat, code red.
红色警报  重复  红色警报
Does anyone copy?
有人收到吗
This is a code red, I repeat, a code red.
红色警报  重复  红色警报
This is a code red, I repeat, a code red. Does anyone copy?
红色警报  重复  红色警报  有人收到吗
We are innocent children and we are trapped under Starcourt Mall.
我们是无辜儿童  困在了星庭商场下方
The Red Army has infiltrated Hawkins, and if we are found,
红军已渗透了霍金斯  如果我们被发现
they will torture and kill us.
会遭到折磨和杀害
[STEVE] Hey. [GRUNTS]
Gotta take it easy on that thing. Gonna drain the battery.
你别一直用那个  会耗尽电池的
- The mall just opened. - So?
-商场刚开门了  -所以呢
So someone could be in range.
所以可能有人在接收范围内
What do you think, Petey the Mall Cop is gonna rappel down here
怎么  你觉得商场保安皮特会用绳子降下来
and save the day?
拯救我们吗
All right, why are you such a cranky pants
好吧  你跟罗宾共度了一晚
after getting to spend the night with Robin?
怎么还那么暴躁
Shh! Jesus Christ.
老天爷
Will you just give up on your creepy dream already?
你能不能放弃那个瘆人的幻想
I heard you guys talking all night.
我听到你俩聊了一整宿
We were trying to figure out a way to open up the door
是啊  你们俩孩子睡觉时
while you children were sleeping.
我们在想办法开电梯门
After eight hours,
经过8小时
we're still exactly nowhere, which is,
我们还是毫无进展
you know, probably just a little bit of the reason
这可能是我稍有些
why I'm feeling just...
暴躁的
- a tad cranky. - [UNZIPPING SOUND]
原因之一
What are you doing?
你在干什么
What does it look like I'm doing? I'm taking a leak. Look away.
你觉得呢  我在撒尿  别看
Look away!
别看
[STEVE'S VOICE ECHOES]
[SCOFFS]
Can you redirect your stream, please?
你能往别的地方瞄吗
[ROBIN'S VOICE ECHOES]
Ugh.
Hey, hey! Be careful, careful, careful!
小心点
We don't even know what that is.
我们都不知道里面是什么
Exactly. It could be useful.
是啊  它或许能派上用场
Useful how?
怎么用
We can survive down here a long time without food,
我们不吃饭  也能在这里活很久
but if the human body doesn't get water, it will die.
但如果人体不摄入水分  就会死的
I hate to break it to you,
真不想戳破
but this is not water.
但这可不是水
No, but it's a liquid,
对  但这是液体
and if it comes down to me drinking that shit
如果要在喝那玩意
or dying of thirst,
和渴死间选择
I drink.
我会喝的
[SCOFFS]
[DISTANT ELECTRONIC WHIRRING]
We've got company.
有人来了
[SUSPENSEFUL SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[BEEPING]
[ELEVATOR DOOR THUDS]
[INDISTINCT FEMALE VOICE ON PA]
[SNIFFING]
[IN RUSSIAN] You smell that?
你闻到了吗
[IN RUSSIAN] What?
什么
Piss.
尿味
[SNIFFING]
[ELEVATOR DOOR WHIRRING]
[STEVE GRUNTS]
Let's go.
我们走
- Go. Go, go, go, go, go. - [ERICA] I'm going!
-走走走  -我走了
- Henderson. Go, go. - [VIAL BUCKLES]
亨德森  走走
[ROBIN] Come on, Steve, let's go!
快点  史蒂夫  我们走
[SIZZLING]
- Jesus Christ. - [ERICA] Ooh!
老天爷
You still wanna drink that?
你还想喝那个吗
Holy mother of God.
老天爷
Well...
好吧
hope you guys are in good shape.
希望你们身体够健壮
Looking at you, roast beef.
说你呢  烤牛肉
Let's go, come on.
我们走吧
Why me?
为什么针对我
维勒家
It was the same thing,
一模一样
the exact same thing that happened to Will last year.
跟去年威尔的状况一模一样
And look at this. Look at the body temperatures.
看啊  看看她的体温
He likes it cold.
他喜欢冷
Okay, so this crazy old woman who was eating fertilizer...
好吧  那么这个吃化肥的疯老太婆
- Mrs. Driscoll. - Right, yeah, Mrs. Driscoll.
-是德里斯科尔太太  -嗯  德里斯科尔太太
- What time was this attack? - Last night.
-她什么时候发作的  -昨晚
Right, but what time last night?
嗯  具体几点
- Around 9:00. - You waited all night to call?
-大概9点  -你等了一整晚才打给我
I was waiting for the doctors to run some tests.
我在等医生做些测试
You weren't there?
你没在吗
Well, I'm here now, aren't I?
我现在不是来了吗
Hallelujah!
哈利路亚
Ooh.
Um, so, wha... what time was your... sauna test?
那么  你们的桑拿测试是几点
[IN UNISON] Around 9:00.
-大概9点  -大概9点
Well, that proves it. That proves my theory.
那就证明了我的理论
She's flayed, just like Billy.
她失灵了  跟比利一样
- Flayed? - The Mind Flayer. He flays people.
-失灵  -吸灵魔  他吸走人的灵魂
Takes over their mind.
控制他们的头脑
Once they do that, they basically become him.
这样一来  他们基本上就变成了他
- If there are two flayed... - We have to assume there are more.
-如果有两人失灵  -那只能认定还有更多人
Heather.
海瑟
Billy was doing something to her.
比利对她做了什么
[HEATHER WHIMPERS ECHO]
She was scared.
她很怕
She was screaming.
她在尖叫
- [SCREAMS] - Bad screams.
叫得很惨
- What's a good scream? - Max said...
-还有叫得不惨吗  -麦克斯说
- Doesn't matter. - I'm sorry, I'm lost. Who is Heather?
-那个不重要  -抱歉  我没跟上  海瑟是谁
- She's a lifeguard at the pool. - Heather Holloway?
-她是泳池的救生员  -海瑟·霍利维吗
[BOTH] Tom.
汤姆
[CAR DOORS SHUT]
Seriously?
不是吧
Welcome to my world.
欢迎来到我的世界
[MIKE SCOFFS]
Seat belts.
系安全带
[INTENSE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[INSECTS BUZZING]
- Oh, my God. Can you not walk so close? - What?
-天呐  你能离我远点吗  -什么
Can you not walk so close to me? You stink.
你走路时离我远点  你好臭
[HOPPER LAUGHS]
I get it, I get it. You're upset, right?
我懂  你在生气  是吗
'Cause I, uh... I blew up the car?
因为我把车炸了
Yeah, with me in it.
是啊  我还在车里呢
Well, I just want to remind you of something, Joyce.
我想提醒你件事  乔伊
- I am not a mechanic. - Yeah, clearly.
-我可不是机械师  -显然的
That's why you should've listened to Alexei.
所以你该听阿列克西的
Oh, right, yeah. Your new boyfriend, right?
是啊  你的新男友  是吧
Yes. Every man I talk to from now on has to be my boyfriend.
是啊  今后每个跟我说话的男人肯定是我男友
Yeah, he reminds me a bit of a Russian Scott Clarke.
他是有点像个苏联版的斯考特·克拉克
Oh, here we go.
又来了
Maybe you should go on a date.
或许你们该去约会
I don't know, I'm thinking, like, Enzo's?
比如说  去恩佐餐厅
- Whoa. - What?
怎么了
He's running.
他跑了
[ALEXEI WHIMPERS, GRUNTS]
You son of a bitch!
你个混蛋
- [ALEXEI MUTTERS IN RUSSIAN] - [HOPPER] Hey! Smirnoff!
司木露
Get back here!
给我回来
- [ALEXEI CHUCKLES] - Hey! C'mere!
过来
[GRUNTING]
[HOPPER] Hey, c'mere!
过来
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[ALL PANTING]
- [BELL CHIMES] - [LIGHT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR BELL JINGLES]
[GRUNTS]
[MAN] You all gonna pay for those?
你要付钱吗
[BURPS]
[REGISTER BEEPING]
So, what are you, some kinda bounty hunter?
你是什么人  赏金猎人吗
I'm a cop.
我是警察
I'm undercover.
我在卧底
[HEAVY METAL PLAYING ON CAR STEREO]
[MUSIC STOPS]
Oh, hey, Karen, it's Joyce.
凯伦  是乔伊
Yeah, I... I'm just checking on Will.
是啊  我想问问威尔
At the movies?
去看电影了
Just keep your mouth shut, all right?
把你的嘴巴闭牢
[SLURPING LOUDLY]
All right, all right, hop in. Come on, get in.
好  好  上车  快  上车
- Hey! - Hey!
You "hey"! You "hey"!
你少来
This is a police emergency, all right?
这可是紧急警方事务
I need to commandeer your vehicle.
我需要征用你的车
What?
什么
As long as there's a... a...
只要...
[HOPPER] What is your name, sir?
你叫什么  先生
- Todd. - Todd?
-托德  -托德
- Yeah. - Todd.
-对  -托德
- Todd. - Todd...
-托德  -托德
listen to me.
听我说
That man in there,
那个人
I know he doesn't look it,
我知道他看上去不像
but he is one of the most dangerous men in the world.
但他是全世界最危险的人之一
He's, uh...
他
- murdered many children. - What?
-杀了好多孩子  -什么
Yeah, he's a true psychopath. I tracked him over two state lines.
是啊  真正的变态  我追着他跨了两州
[JOYCE] Hey, what's going on?
怎么回事
Ah, Detective Byers.
拜耶斯警探
Uh...
this is Todd.
这是托德
He's agreed to...
他答应把车借给我们
lend us his vehicle to transport our dangerous criminal.
好转移这位危险罪犯
Oh, yes, he... very dangerous, uh,
是啊  他非常危险
forger... er.
是个伪造犯
Yeah. Uh, child murderer.
是啊  是儿童谋杀犯
- Child murderer? - We should really get going.
-什么  -我们该走了
Hey, how do I get my car back?
我怎么拿回我的车
- You just call the station. - What station?
-联系警局  -哪个警局
- [HEAVY METAL RESUMES] - Ooh, I like the sound of that, Todd!
这歌太好听了  托德
Hey, what station?
哪个警局
You're doing the right thing!
你在做好事
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Hey, what the... Hey!
搞什么...
Dude!
什么鬼
[DUSTIN] I mean, you have to admit, as a feat of engineering alone,
你得承认  光是工程上的成就
this is impressive.
就已经颇为惊人了
What are you talking about? It's a total fire hazard.
你说什么呢  这根本是消防隐患
There's no stairs, there's no exit,
没有楼梯  没有出口
there's just an elevator that drops you halfway to hell.
只有一台把你降到地狱半途的电梯
They're Commies.
他们是共党
You don't pay people, they cut corners.
不给钱  工人就会偷工减料
To be fair to our Russian comrades,
要为苏联同志们说句话
I don't think this tunnel was designed for walking.
这条隧道应该不是让你走的
Think about it, they developed the perfect system
想想看  他们开发了运送那种货物的
for transporting that cargo.
完美体系
It all comes into the mall like any old delivery.
像所有普通货物那样被送到商场
And then they load it up onto those trucks and nobody's the wiser.
然后装载上那种卡车 神不知鬼不觉
[STEVE] You think they built this whole mall
你觉得他们建了个商场
so they could transport that green poison?
就为了运输那种绿色毒液吗
I very seriously doubt it's something as boring as poison.
我非常怀疑那玩意只是毒液那么简单
It's gotta be much more valuable, like promethium or something.
肯定贵重得多  像是钷什么的
What the hell is promethium?
钷是什么
It's what Victor Stone's dad used to make
维克托·斯通的爸爸
Cyborg's bionic and cybernetic components.
用它来制作半机械人的仿生和控制部件
You're all so nerdy, it makes me physically ill.
你们都好书呆  我都不舒服了
No, no, no. No, don't lump me in with them.
不不  别把我跟他们归在一起
I'm not a nerd, all right?
我可不是书呆子
[ROBIN] Why so sensitive, Harrington?
干吗这么敏感  哈灵顿
Afraid of losing cool points to a ten-year-old child?
怕在10岁孩子面前掉价吗
No, I'm just saying I don't know jack shit about Prometheus.
不  我只是说  我完全不知道什么叫普罗米修斯
[DUSTIN] Promethium.
是钷
Prometheus is a Greek mythological figure, but whatever.
普罗米修斯是希腊神话里的人物
All I'm saying is,
随便了  我就是说
it's probably being used to make something.
那玩意可能是用来制造什么的原料
Or power something.
或是驱动什么
- Like a nuclear weapon? - Totally.
-就像核武吗  -对
Walking towards a nuclear weapon. That's great.
走向核武  好啊
- That'd be great. - But if they're building something,
-太好了  -但如果他们在建造什么
why here?
为什么选这里
I mean, Hawkins. Seriously. Of all places.
偏偏要来霍金斯啊  不是吧
At the very best, we're a toilet stop on your way to Disneyland,
我们说好了也就是去迪士尼乐园路上的休息站
but maybe that's it. Maybe it's our very...
但或许就是这样  或许是我们...
- You think the Russians know? - About...
-你觉得苏联人知道了吗  -关于...
- They could. - So it's connected?
-有可能  -那么有关吗
- Maybe. - How?
-或许吧  -怎么会
I don't know, but it's...
我不知道  但是
[BOTH] Possible.
有可能
I'm sorry, is there something you'd like to share with the class?
抱歉  你们有什么想告诉全班同学的吗
- [STATIC HISSING] - [MAN SPEAKS RUSSIAN ON RADIO]
[BOTH] Walkie.
对讲机
[MAN CONTINUES IN RUSSIAN]
[IN RUSSIAN] "A trip to China sounds nice."
"去中国听上去不错
If you tread lightly."
只要你轻轻走"
It's the code.
是那个密语
- Wherever that broadcast is coming from... - It's close.
-放送的信号源  -就在附近
And if there's one thing we know about that signal...
我们知道那个信号...
It can reach the surface.
能达到地表
Let's go.
我们走
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
[LOW FREQUENCY VIBRATION]
Tom?
汤姆
Heather?
海瑟
Jesus, it's freezing.
天呐  好冷
[SNIFFS] Do you guys smell that?
你们闻到了吗
[ALL SNIFFING]
Oh.
Oh, God.
天呐
More chemicals.
又是化学品
You think they're guzzling this shit?
你觉得他们是在吃这玩意吗
Yeah, either that or they just went on a hell of a cleaning spree.
不然的话
他们就是疯狂清洁了一番
But last year, Will didn't eat chemicals.
但去年  威尔可没吃化学品
- Did you? - No.
-是吧  -对
This is something new.
这是新情况
Mr. Clarke, fifth grade. Posit.
克拉克老师  五年级  假设
What happens when you mix chemicals together?
把化学品混在一起能得到什么
[LUCAS AND WILL] You create a new substance.
创造新物质
- What if they're making something? - [MAX] In themselves?
-如果他们在制作什么东西呢  -在身体里吗
I mean, come on, if you drink this crap, it'll kill you.
拜托  喝这玩意会死人的
Yeah, if you're human.
是啊  如果你是人类
[DISTANT, FAINT PULSING]
[NANCY] Blood.
血
Yesterday,
昨天
Tom had a bandage on his forehead.
汤姆前额帖了块胶布
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
He was attacked.
他被袭击了
Call 91... [GRUNTS]
快报警
[THUNDERCLAP]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC INTENSIFIES]
[DOOR HINGE CREAKS]
They must have tied them.
他们肯定是被绑了起来
They must have taken them somewhere.
然后被带去了某处
[THUNDERCLAP]
Mrs. Driscoll.
德里斯科尔太太
She kept saying...
她一直说
"I have to go back."
"我必须回去"
[SHRIEKS]
What if the flaying,
如果吸灵
it's taking place somewhere else?
是发生在别处的呢
There must be a place where all this started, right?
肯定有个一切开始的地方  是吧
A source.
一个源头
Somewhere he didn't want me to see.
他不希望我看到的地方
[FAINT SHRIEKING NOISE]
If we can find the source, then maybe we can stop him.
如果我们能找到  或许就能阻止他
Or at least stop it from spreading
至少也阻止它的传播
or doing whatever the hell he's doing with those chemicals.
或是阻止它用那些化学品做不管什么事
How do we find it?
我们怎么找到
Mrs. Driscoll.
德里斯科尔太太
If she wants to go back so badly, why don't we let her?
如果她那么想回去  我们放她走呢
[TODD] ... this guy comes up to me,
这人就走过来
I'm just pumping gas over here,
我就在这里加油
and he... Hey, whoa!
他...
Don't cross me right now!
现在别惹我
- [BELL JINGLES] - [LIGHT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CASH REGISTER BEEPING]
Busy day?
今天忙吗
You could say that.
可以这么说吧
Some psycho stole that dude's car.
有个疯子偷了那人的车
What else?
还有什么
- What? - What else did he say?
-什么  -他还说了什么
This psycho?
那个疯子
No offense, but I already went over all this with the cops.
别介意  但我已经跟警察都说过了
I'm not a cop.
我不是警察
Yeah, no shit, Khrushchev.
是啊  赫鲁晓夫
[GRUNTS] Oh, shit!
该死
[WHIMPERS]
[GRIGORI] Don't look at them.
别看他们
At me.
看我
Tell me
告诉我
about this psycho.
那个疯子怎么了
[PANTING]
Come on, let's go.
走
Move it.
快点
[DOORS SLAM]
I thought you said this guy was a journalist.
你不是说这人是个记者吗
Yeah, he, uh... he was.
是啊  曾经是
Was?
曾经
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[MURRAY] Look at the camera.
看镜头
The camera, above you to the right.
镜头  在你右上方
Identify yourselves.
上报身份
Jim Hopper, Joyce Byers,
吉姆·霍普  乔伊·拜耶斯
Smirnoff.
司木露
- Alexei. - Alexei.
-是阿列克西  -阿列克西
[MURRAY] Surname.
姓氏
I don't know.
我不知道
Family name!
就是家族名的意思
Yeah, I know. I told... I don't know, okay?
我知道  我不知道  好吗
Open the damn door!
快开门
[JOYCE] Hopper.
霍普
It's all right. Don't worry.
没事  别担心
He's a little bit eccentric, but...
他有点古怪  但是
he's completely harmless.
完全无害的
- [SHOTGUN COCKS] - [JOYCE GASPS]
Name.
姓名
[IN RUSSIAN] Get that out of my face,
把那玩意从我面前拿开
you bald American pig.
你个美国秃头猪
[IN RUSSIAN] I may be bald,
我虽然秃头
but you're the one in handcuffs,
但你戴着手铐呢
Soviet scum.
苏联人渣
[IN ENGLISH] Hi, Jim.
吉姆
[BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING]
Wait.
等等
[DEVICE BEEPS AND WHINES]
[ELECTRIC CRACKLING]
[DEVICE WHIRS]
[DEVICE BEEPS]
[LOUD BEEPING]
[IN RUSSIAN] Watch it.
小心点
[IN RUSSIAN] Silence, scum.
安静  人渣
- How long is this gonna take, because I... - No.
-这得要多久  因为我  -不
- No. - No.
-不  -不
- No, you do not get to question me. - [DEVICE BEEPS]
不  你无权向我提问
You have dragged an enemy of the state into my home
你把一个国家敌人拖进了我家
as carelessly as a child drags in shit on his shoe.
就像个孩子把沾在鞋上的屎带进屋来一样不小心
I will search him until I am satisfied.
我要搜他搜到满意
[CLEARS THROAT] Jim. C'mere.
吉姆  过来
[JOYCE] Just c'mere. I need to talk to you.
过来一下  我跟你说句话
[HOPPER] Yeah, what?
怎么了
- What? - This is not gonna work.
-怎么了  -这不行的
- What do you mean? - He's not eccentric, he's certifiable.
-什么意思  -他不是古怪  是疯了
[LOUD BEEPING]
- Glass houses, Joyce. - What?
-你还说别人  乔伊  -什么
- You know, pot calling the kettle black. - Oh, come on.
-五十步笑百步  -拜托
- Excuse me! - What?
-喂  -怎么了
Do me a favor and move your lovers' quarrel elsewhere.
帮个忙  小两口拌嘴去别处
- Oh, oh, this? - No, no, no.
-我们  -不不
Not a lovers' quarrel, pal.
我们不是小两口拌嘴
Spare me!
少来了
What is your problem?
你有什么毛病
Please, stop talking!
请别说话了
No! We have had a very long day.
不  我们今天非常漫长
We have been shot at, nearly blown up,
我们被人射击  差点炸飞
walked God knows how many miles in a hundred degree heat,
顶着酷热走了天知道多久
stole a car,
偷了辆车
all while being chased by this gigantic... psychopath,
同时还有个大块头疯子追着我们
all so we could bring him to you.
就为了带他来见你
Because somehow, you're the closest person who speaks Russian,
因为不知怎么  你是会俄语的最近的人
which I can't believe.
真是难以置信
But that doesn't matter because, unfortunately, we're here.
但那无所谓了  因为很不幸  我们来都来了
So, if you don't mind,
所以  如果你不介意
put that thing away,
把那玩意放起来
stop behaving like a jackass, and ask him what he's doing
别犯浑了  问他  他在干什么
that's making my magnets fall off my damn fridge!
害我的磁铁都从冰箱上掉下来了
Please.
拜托
[DEVICE WHINES]
[BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYS LOUDLY]
[INDISTINCT MALE VOICE ON PA]
Okay, clear.
好了  安全
Clear, come on, let's go.
安全  我们走
[ROBIN] Okay, that was close.
刚刚好悬
- [DUSTIN] Too close. - Relax.
-太悬了  -放松
All right? Relax. Nobody saw...
好吗  放松  没人看...
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING RUSSIAN ON PA]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[STEVE] Shit.
该死
Jesus!
天呐
- Red Dawn. - I saw it.
-《红色黎明》  -我看到了
- First floor, northwest. - Saw what?
-一楼  西北  -看到什么了
The comms room.
通讯室
You saw the comms room?
你看到通讯室了
Correct.
没错
- Are you sure? - Positive. The door was open for a second,
-你确定吗  -确定  门就开了一下
and I saw a bunch of lights and machines and shit in there.
我看到里面有一堆灯光  机器什么的
That could be a hundred different things.
那有数百种可能性呢
I'll take those odds.
我愿冒险
[SIGHS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[STEVE WHISPERS] All right.
好吧
We're gonna move fast, we're gonna stay low.
我们得快点行动  保持低调
- Okay? - Okay.
-好吗  -好
[WOMAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Shh!
Move it.
快走
[DOOR PANEL BEEPS]
Let's go.
走
Sh, sh. Come on.
快来
[FEMALE VOICE SPEAKING RUSSIAN ON RADIO]
[IN RUSSIAN] Tread lightly!
轻轻走
Tread lightly!
[IN RUSSIAN] Who are you?
你是谁
Silver cat... Silver cat.
银猫  银猫
I don't understand.
我不懂
- China? - [MAN SCOFFS]
中国
[YELLS]
- [MAN GRUNTS] - [STEVE GROANS]
[STEVE GRUNTS]
- [MAN YELLS] - [STEVE GRUNTS]
[MAN GROANS]
[PANTING]
[DUSTIN] Dude!
哥们
You did it!
你做到了
You won a fight!
你打赢了
[STEVE] Jeez...
天呐
[LAUGHS SOFTLY]
[STEVE CHUCKLES]
- What are you doing? - Getting us our ticket out of here.
-你在干什么  -拿钥匙卡好逃走
You want to walk all the way back?
你想再一路走回去吗
Well, we can hang out for a little bit, relax, have a picnic maybe.
我们可以在这里再待会儿  放松  吃顿野餐什么的
Have a picnic? We came here for the radio.
吃野餐  我们是为了无线电来的
[DUSTIN] This plan is way better.
这个计划好多了
If I knew Steve could knock out a Russian,
如果我知道史蒂夫能干倒苏联人
that would've been our plan in the first place.
就会把那当成原计划了
[LOW FREQUENCY PULSING]
[MEN SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
- ... but I guess you're... - Guys.
-但我猜...  -伙计们
There's something up there.
上面有东西
[STEVE] Let's go.
我们走
[MEN SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Holy shit.
我去
[LOW FREQUENCY PULSING CONTINUES]
[BREATHING MASKS HISSING]
[ELECTRIC CRACKLING]
[LOUD THRUMMING]
[CRACKING NOISE]
[LOUD SHRIEKING SOUND]
[WOMAN] No, that is not mean.
不  那不叫刻薄
That is honest.
那叫诚实
She won't find out.
她不会知道的
See, you're the only one who gon' tell...
瞧  只有你
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Excuse me!
会说...喂喂  干什么呢
Where do you think you're going?
你们想去哪
Oh, um...
I was just going to visit my grandma again.
我又是来见奶奶的
And... And this...
这是
this is my family.
我的家人
- Extended. - I don't care who they are.
-亲戚  -我不管他们是谁
You know the rules. Two visitors at a time.
你清楚规矩  一次两人探视
- Yeah, but... - Two!
-是啊  但是  -两人
Girl, this child has lost her mind.
妹子  这孩子是疯了
She brought a whole zoo in here.
她带了一堆人进来
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
[LIGHT MUZAK PLAYING]
You know,
知道吗
those things that I said yesterday, I...
我昨天说的那些话
I didn't mean them.
我不是真心的
- I know. - I don't think you're like those assholes.
-我知道  -我不觉得你跟那些混蛋一样
At all.
一点也不像
I never have. I...
我从未那么想
- I was just... - Angry?
-我就是  -生气了
Which I still don't get.
我还是不懂
I mean, I was just completely, utterly,
我完全  彻底
mortifyingly...
丢人的
wrong.
错了
Don't let that go to your head.
别被冲昏头了
I won't.
不会的
I just look forward to you never doubting me again.
我就是希望待你再不会质疑我
[ELEVATOR DINGS]
[VENDING MACHINE WHIRRING]
Oh, come on, you piece of shit!
拜托  你个破玩意
[LOW FREQUENCY VIBRATION]
Thanks.
谢谢
Dude, I think that was it.
哥们  我觉得那就是了
That was what?
是什么
The olive branch.
橄榄枝
The what?
什么
Oh, my God.
天呐
You're hopeless.
你真没救
Okay,
好吧
[WHISPERS] I'll distract Max,
我去引开麦克斯
get you an opening.
给你个机会
And then talk to her. All right?
你去跟她谈谈  好吗
[CANDY WRAPPERS CRINKLING]
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
Where is she?
她人呢
I don't know.
我不知道
- Are you sure this is the right room? - Yeah.
-你确定是这个房间吗  -对
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
[TOM] She's gone home.
她回家了
We were hoping you might come back.
我们就希望你们还会再来
Whose blood is that?
那是谁的血
Tom, whatever you've done, it's not you.
汤姆  不管你做了什么  那不是你
He's making you do this.
是他在逼你
[JONATHAN GRUNTS]
Go!
快跑
[NANCY GASPS]
Owie.
矮油
Go, go, go!
快跑
[BOTH PANTING]
- [STAIRWELL DOOR SHUTS] - Run!
跑
Yeah! [LAUGHS]
棒
- [MAX] Got it, two in a row. - [LUCAS] That was good, that was good.
-接到了  连续两个  -厉害  厉害
[MAX AND LUCAS CHEERING]
[LUCAS SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
- [MAX] Best three in a row now. - Hey.
连续三个了
Hi.
Does your species like M&M's?
你们物种喜欢MM豆吗
[GENTLE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
I like the new look, by the way. It's cool.
我喜欢你的新造型  很酷
Thanks.
谢谢
[BOTH PANTING]
[JONATHAN] Run!
跑
[JONATHAN] This way, this way!
这边  这边
[BOTH PANTING]
Nancy!
南茜
- [INTERCOM BUZZER SOUNDS] - Hello? Hello?!
有人吗  有人吗
Here.
这边
[BOTH PANTING]
It's ringing.
响了
I don't care how good her pie is.
我才不管她的派多好吃
No, I don't want her in my damn house.
不  我不要她进我家
Come on, pick up!
快接听
Nancy?
南茜
[NANCY GASPS]
- Hi there. - [GLASS SHATTERING]
你好
[RINGING TONE]
[NANCY GASPS]
I'm here for you, Nancy Drew.
我来抓你了  神探南茜
[NANCY WHIMPERS]
[JONATHAN GRUNTS, GROANS]
- No! [GRUNTS] - [GLASS SHATTERS]
不要
[JONATHAN CHOKING]
[JONATHAN GRUNTS, GROANS]
[BRUCE SNARLS]
Jonathan!
乔纳森
[NANCY YELPS]
[PANTING]
- [BREATHING RAPIDLY] - [GASPS]
- [NANCY YELLS] - [BRUCE GROANS]
[BRUCE GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
- You bitch. - [JONATHAN] Nancy!
-你个贱人  -南茜
- [JONATHAN] Run! - [NANCY WHIMPERS]
跑
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
Help! Help!
救命  救命
Help!
救命
Is anyone here?!
有人在吗
Nancy.
南茜
[BRUCE] Nancy!
[NANCY WHIMPERS]
[STRAINING GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS, COUGHS]
[ECHOING] Where are you going?
你想去哪
[PANTING]
[GRUNTS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[TOM INHALES SHARPLY]
[TOM YELLS]
[GRUNTS]
Yoo-hoo.
Nancy Drew, where are you?
神探南茜  你在哪
[JONATHAN GROANS]
[GRUNTS, GASPS]
[TOM GRUNTS]
Nancy.
南茜
[GRUNTING]
[TOM PANTING MENACINGLY]
[JONATHAN WHIMPERS]
[BRUCE] Marco...
马可
Marco...
[NANCY] Polo!
波罗
Huh?
☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[GRUNTS]
[MOANING]
[GROANING]
- [NANCY YELLS] - [TOM GROANS]
[TOM GRUNTS]
Go... to... hell!
下  地  狱  吧
[CHOKING]
[TOM CHOKING]
[PANTING]
[ELECTRICAL DRONING]
[GASPS]
[RECEPTIONIST SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY]
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[GROANING]
[GRUNTING]
[BRUCE CONTINUES GRUNTING]
[CHITTERING SOUND]
[GROANING]
[SQUELCHING SOUND]
[BABBLING]
[BRUCE GRUNTS FAINTLY]
[PANTING]
[SQUELCHING SOUND]
[CHITTERING AND SQUELCHING]
[CHITTERING SOUND CONTINUES]
[EMERGENCY LIGHTS CLICKING]
[LOW GROWLING]
[SHRIEKING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[MONKEY SCREECHING]